# **ROB DIMSDALE**

San Francisco, California, US

robert.dimsdale@gmail.com https://robdimsdale.com

https://github.com/robdimsdale https://twitter.com/robdimsdale https://linkedin.com/in/robdimsdale

#### **ABOUT**

I'm Rob Dimsdale, a software developer currently based near San Francisco where I work for Pivotal on the Cloud Foundry project. Previously I have worked for Oracle in the Tape Storage division in Colorado and Softwire in London, UK. My primary areas of focus are web applications (mainly Java, some Go and Ruby) and systems-administration, though I'm interested in various languages and technologies from MATLAB and Python all the way down to embedded C projects and audio circuitry.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

## Pivotal, Cloud Foundry, Jun. 2014-Present, Software Engineer

DevOps on services team for OSS and commercial products, working primarily with Go, Ruby and Bash.

- Designed and implemented TCP Proxy in Go.
- · Adding support for RiakCS.
- Extending MySQL/MariaDB to incorporate high-availability.
- Migrating continuous integration from Jenkins to GoCD.

## Oracle, Tape Library Systems, Oct. 2012-Jun. 2014, Software Engineer

Server-side web developer and sysadmin for design and implementation of a new control system for tape libraries.

- Responsible for developing core behavior, architecting code, internal/external API definition and implementation and hardware simulation.
- Technology stack consisted of Java EE, Oracle DB, TopLink and Weblogic.
- Devised and maintained development environment and build process, including continous integration.
- Role also included educating team members on language and framework features and agile practices.

# Softwire Technology Ltd, Sep. 2011-Oct. 2012, Software Engineer

Web developer (mostly server-side, some front-end) for bespoke/custom web applications.

- Developed content management system and API for high profile BBC /music/events website using Spring, MySQL, Hibernate and Tomcat. Delivered ahead of schedule.
- Architected, developed and managed a web application to collect and display statistics on phone calls handled by in-house sales team, using Spring, MySQL, Hibernate, Tomcat and Javascript. Delivered on schedule.
- Enhanced major international retailer's online shop website, incorporating Spring, Microsoft SQL, Hibernate and Tomcat. Rapid comprehension of large existing codebase resulted in delivery significantly ahead of schedule.

**Inmarsat**, Summer 2010, Software Developer Application developer. Rob Dimsdale Page 2

 Developed C++ application for performing offline analysis of satellite payload using FFTs to model satelite payload for 2010 Brazillian presidential election. Delivered on schedule, with 95%-accurate prediction for data usage profiles.

# Pace PLC, Summer 2009, Software Developer

Embedded developer.

Converted MATLAB model of 802.11g data transmitter/receiver to C as preparation for embedding into ARM processor, devising new implementations of proprietary algorithms provided by MATLAB libraries. Delivered ahead of schedule.

## Personal Projects, Sep. 2012-Present, DevOps

Personal projects of note.

- Wundergo A client library for the Wunderlist API written in Golang.
- Angular-resume Javascript application to assist with creation of a json-resume, using Angular Schema Form. https://github.com/robdimsdale/angular-resume
- Garage-pi A webserver written in Go to display output of Raspberry Pi camera module and trigger gpio. A typical use would be to view the interior of a garage and trigger the garage door opener via gpio (and a relay). https://github.com/robdimsdale/garage-pi
- Rentchecker An android application and java executable to connect to the web-portal provided by the leasers of my apartment, scrape the HTML and display any rent/utilities due. Uses Spring for Android. https://github.com/robdimsdale/rentchecker
- Evernote Listener A web application to listen for web hooks from Evernote, automatically
  exporting the updated contents of a specific notebook as HTML. Also includes a read-only
  api to display meta-data via both json and a webapp. Technologies include Java, Spring,
  Tomcat, shell-scripting and AppleScript, HTML/CSS/Javascript and Android.

### **SKILLS**

### Languages

Java, Go, Ruby, Python, Javascript, C#, C/C++, SQL, MATLAB, Bash/Shell

## **Build Tools**

Maven, Gradle, Ant, Git, Subversion, Hudson/Jenkins, GoCD

## **Databases**

MySQL/MariaDB, Oracle, Postgres

#### Infrastructure

Cloud Foundry, Weblogic, Tomcat, Apache HTTP Server

## **Operating Systems**

Linux, Windows, OS X

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Cambridge, UK, MEng, Engineering: Electrical & Information Sciences, 2011